<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Samrat Man Singh</title><link>http://samrat.me/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://samrat.me/feeds/kickstarter.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0545</lastBuildDate><item><title>Help me buy a domain name</title><link>http://samrat.me/blog/2012/07/help-me-buy-a-domain-name</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE- &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=Udo"&gt;Udo&lt;/a&gt; on Hacker News was kind enough to buy me a domain. This site can now be reached at &lt;a href="http://samrat.me"&gt;http://samrat.me&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks a lot, Udo.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got a problem. I want to buy a domain name for this website. But due to some banking regulations in my country, online payments cannot be made(for international transactions, at least.) Some companies &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; making money by buying products on Amazon and other online shops on behalf of people here, but they're limited to only physical goods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This problem has been troubling me for a while, and I've come up with what could be a solution. Following all the recent buzz around Kickstarter- I decided to ask the Internet for help, but don't worry, &lt;strong&gt;I'm not asking for your money&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're still reading this and interested in helping &lt;em&gt;and if you happen to be a person who is about to buy a domain name&lt;/em&gt;, you can support my cause by buying a domain name with my &lt;a href="http://www.namecheap.com?aff=34707"&gt;affiliate link&lt;/a&gt; on Namecheap. That way, a small percentage of what you spend on Namecheap might help me get a domain name for myself. But if you're not interested, no pressure, I can live without a domain name; just please don't take this the wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in helping but not looking to register a domain name right now, you could bookmark the link above and use that to make your purchase later. As you can probably tell, I haven't used Namecheap but I've heard they're great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samrat Man Singh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>tag:samrat.me,2012-07-07:blog/2012/07/help-me-buy-a-domain-name</guid><category>miscellaneous</category><category>kickstarter</category><category>domain-name</category></item></channel></rss>