<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Samrat Man Singh</title><link>http://samrat.me/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://samrat.me/feeds/miscellaneous.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0545</lastBuildDate><item><title>Help me buy a domain name</title><link>http://samrat.me/blog/2012/07/help-me-buy-a-domain-name</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE- &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=Udo"&gt;Udo&lt;/a&gt; on Hacker News was kind enough to buy me a domain. This site can now be reached at &lt;a href="http://samrat.me"&gt;http://samrat.me&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks a lot, Udo.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got a problem. I want to buy a domain name for this website. But due to some banking regulations in my country, online payments cannot be made(for international transactions, at least.) Some companies &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; making money by buying products on Amazon and other online shops on behalf of people here, but they're limited to only physical goods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This problem has been troubling me for a while, and I've come up with what could be a solution. Following all the recent buzz around Kickstarter- I decided to ask the Internet for help, but don't worry, &lt;strong&gt;I'm not asking for your money&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're still reading this and interested in helping &lt;em&gt;and if you happen to be a person who is about to buy a domain name&lt;/em&gt;, you can support my cause by buying a domain name with my &lt;a href="http://www.namecheap.com?aff=34707"&gt;affiliate link&lt;/a&gt; on Namecheap. That way, a small percentage of what you spend on Namecheap might help me get a domain name for myself. But if you're not interested, no pressure, I can live without a domain name; just please don't take this the wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in helping but not looking to register a domain name right now, you could bookmark the link above and use that to make your purchase later. As you can probably tell, I haven't used Namecheap but I've heard they're great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samrat Man Singh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>tag:samrat.me,2012-07-07:blog/2012/07/help-me-buy-a-domain-name</guid><category>miscellaneous</category><category>kickstarter</category><category>domain-name</category></item><item><title>Google's answer to Siri: Now</title><link>http://samrat.me/blog/2012/06/googles-answer-to-siri-now</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you've been following the tech world recently you'd know that Apple and Google haven't been the best of friends lately. You know, because Google ripped off Apple the same way Microsoft had ripped them off back when the PC boom was kicking off. There's a statement by Steve Jobs in his biography which can only be regarded as a declaration of war on Google. And we are starting to actually see this war taking place- a few weeks ago, Apple declared that the new iOS will come with its own 'Google Maps'-like service instead of Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, Google too has announced its answer to what was iOS 5's most famous addition- Siri. It's not exactly like Siri- in fact, Google has tried to go a step further and make a more smarter system. If Google succeeds in rolling out Project Glass then Google Now will be a pretty nifty feature for it too. Watch the video below to find out what Now is all about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/pPqliPzHYyc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samrat Man Singh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>tag:samrat.me,2012-06-28:blog/2012/06/googles-answer-to-siri-now</guid><category>miscellaneous</category><category>google</category><category>apple</category></item><item><title>Every minute of the day...</title><link>http://samrat.me/blog/2012/06/every-minute-of-the-day</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I found this totally neat infograph today on &lt;a href="http://www.visualnews.com/2012/06/19/how-much-data-created-every-minute/?view=infographic"&gt;Visual News&lt;/a&gt; and thought I'd share it with you guys. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.visualnews.com/2012/06/19/how-much-data-created-every-minute/?view=infographic"&gt;&lt;img src="http://visualnews.columnfivemedia.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/DOMO-Data-in-One-Minute.jpg" style="width:675px; padding:10px;"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, for a shameless plug: you might want to check out a web app I made a few weeks ago that helps you put into context how fast video is being added to Youtube- &lt;a href="http://omgyoutube.herokuapp.com/"&gt;OMGYoutube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samrat Man Singh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2012 12:05:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>tag:samrat.me,2012-06-23:blog/2012/06/every-minute-of-the-day</guid><category>miscellaneous</category></item><item><title>Would you want to be on Svbtle?</title><link>http://samrat.me/blog/2012/05/would-you-want-to-be-on-svbtle</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When I first saw the Hacker News &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3742314"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href="http://svbtle.com/"&gt;Svbtle&lt;/a&gt;, I opened it. Svbtle looked interesting, maybe something I'd want to use but then came the part about it being only for a small number of "vetted bloggers" and like so many others I was dissapointed. The design looked so good, it was a shame I couldn't use it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon, &lt;em&gt;the debate&lt;/em&gt; had already started. As I said, I wasn't the only one dissapointed that it was a closed system- everyone seemed to be complaining, but &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3744237"&gt;someone else&lt;/a&gt; had gone a step ahead and built something similar called &lt;a href="http://natewienert.com/codename-obtvse"&gt;Obtvse&lt;/a&gt; and released its code. Svbtle became the &lt;strong&gt;hot story&lt;/strong&gt; on Hacker News; even TechCrunch ran a &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/24/forget-todays-drama-dustin-curtis-svbtle-is-trying-to-push-blogging-forward/"&gt;piece on it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how has things changed since I first read Dustin Curtis' post about Suvbtle? Well, now I don't really want to be on it. It's just gotten too much publicity and now the guys who are already in, the &lt;em&gt;vetted bloggers&lt;/em&gt; who were &lt;em&gt;witty and intelligent&lt;/em&gt; enough to get invited, kind of look like the bad guys. Regardless of how awesome the design is(yeah, I still the think the design is really neat), right now I think having the Svbtle brand name on my site is not something I'd want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you guys think? Would you want to be on Svbtle?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samrat Man Singh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 18:15:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>tag:samrat.me,2012-05-03:blog/2012/05/would-you-want-to-be-on-svbtle</guid><category>miscellaneous</category></item><item><title>A world without LEGO</title><link>http://samrat.me/blog/2011/10/a-world-without-lego</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I just read this short but really thoughtful &lt;a href="http://sahillavingia.com/blog/why-im-scared-of-the-post-pc-era/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://sahillavingia.com/"&gt;Sahil Lavingia&lt;/a&gt; and couldn't agree with it more. A lot of the products we use today are products of the &lt;a href="http://catb.org/~esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html"&gt;hacker mindset&lt;/a&gt;- the personal computer, Facebook, Google. All these are here today because some guy or guys didn't just sit around waiting for some big company to make something they wanted but instead, went ahead and built what they had needed. In fact, they built it even when there were big companies building such things, just because they knew they could build a better product than those that already existed. And they built those things, despite the fact that they didn't have even a small fraction of the resources the large corporations had. And then, they built it and eventually even outgrew those very corporations. Yahoo Mail now has a &lt;em&gt;Sign in with Google&lt;/em&gt; option!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things like LEGO blocks teach us that we can go beyond being users to become builders. However, as more people "start their technology career with iPads" and their Internet careers with Facebook, the tech industry might lose the enthusiastic innovation and curiosity it is now filled with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"But hopefully I am wrong." Well, I really hope he is.  &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samrat Man Singh</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 18:15:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>tag:samrat.me,2011-10-14:blog/2011/10/a-world-without-lego</guid><category>miscellaneous</category></item><item><title>The Gamification of Games</title><link>http://samrat.me/blog/2011/10/the-gamification-of-games</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On the front page of Hacker News I saw an item today: &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3114239"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who killed videogames? How games are getting more addictive but not fun&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. And frankly, I haven’t even read the “ghost story” yet. Still, I think I get from the elaborated title what the article is going to say. I’d also recently read &lt;a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2011/10/the-gamification.html"&gt;The Gamification&lt;/a&gt; on Coding Horror (which is actually not quite related to the context) and I couldn’t help make an association here between, and this is going to sound weird, games and gamification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last one or two years games like Farmville, Angry Birds, Doodle Jump suddenly started getting a lot of attention. Those games got downloaded or played by millions of people. Obviously, a huge part of their success is due to the successful platforms they were built for, but the reason so many people have become hooked on to these games is actually how they are built to be addictive. The developers of these have put visibly much more focus on the addictiveness of the game, than say Age of Empires or Counter Strike. Of course, I do not mean to imply that those games aren’t fun or addictive. The thing is, gamers would fall in love with these games. But no one really “loves” Farmville  they just become obsessed with it. And while, games like Angry Birds are mighty time-killers they just don’t arouse the enthusiasm games like Call of Duty did. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why is there such a drastic change in how games are built? The answer: Money. Before, the way game developers made money was by selling the game on a CD or DVD. Today the game itself is available for free, but game companies have figured out newer, more valuable ways to mine money out of these games. And the way they made money, required the players to be very involved in those games. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zynga"&gt;Zynga&lt;/a&gt;, the company behind Farmville makes money by selling virtual goods in the game(Zynga's business model is explained in much detail &lt;a href="http://www.financemanila.net/2011/02/how-does-zynga-make-money-their-business-model-and-revenues/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). This is the same business model that carrier companies like AT&amp;amp;T use these days. They give you shiny smartphones at low prices and then mine money off you from your data usage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What all this means is that game companies have an incentive to get you addicted to the game, whatever it takes. And they are doing it really well. According to Wikipedia, “As of July 2011, Zynga's games on Facebook have over 232 million monthly active users.” and it’s valued at $15 billion to $20 billion. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rovio"&gt;Rovio(Angry Birds)&lt;/a&gt; whose business model has been speculated &lt;a href="http://answers.onstartups.com/questions/22420/how-does-rovio-angry-birds-make-money/22434#22434"&gt;in this OnStartups answer&lt;/a&gt; also has had really high profits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What these companies have done, for good or for bad, is figured out how to successfully make a lot of money in the gaming industry. And the way they did it was by gamifying games. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samrat Man Singh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 18:15:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>tag:samrat.me,2011-10-13:blog/2011/10/the-gamification-of-games</guid><category>miscellaneous</category></item></channel></rss>