<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Samrat Man Singh</title><link>http://samrat.me/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://samrat.me/feeds/reviews.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 18:15:00 +0545</lastBuildDate><item><title>Newsblur, an awesome alternative to Google Reader</title><link>http://samrat.me/blog/2011/08/newsblur-an-awesome-alternative-to-google-reader</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've recently &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=2805152"&gt;discovered&lt;/a&gt; a new web app called &lt;a href="http://newsblur.com"&gt;Newsblur&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, Newsblur is a feed reader and aims to solve many problems Google Reader doesn't. Newsblur gives you the option of viewing the original website page along with the feed, so you can browse through the feed to see if anything interests you and then, see the actual webpage inside Newsblur itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsblur also has this cool little feature called Intelligence Trainer. What you can do with it is that you can train Newsblur, to find articles from your subscriptions that are potentially interesting to you.  You can train the Newsblur Intelligence by 'liking' a tag or an author or other pieces of metadata. And by doing so, you'll help Newsblur identify similar items that could be interesting to you. More importantly, it helps you discard items which you wouldn't want to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can join Newsblur for free, however the free account has a limit of 64 subscriptions; you can also get a paid Premium account. I have used a free account for a while and my experience with it so far has been pretty fine. Its much faster than Google Reader and with its features, it helps me reach the &lt;em&gt;important content&lt;/em&gt; faster. However, it is a work in progress and thus some features like organizing feeds into folders, sending articles to Instapaper still need polishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsblur is an &lt;a href="http://github.com/samuelclay/NewsBlur/"&gt;opensource project&lt;/a&gt; by Samuel Clay(&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/samuelclay"&gt;@samuelclay&lt;/a&gt;). Check it out, if you use Google Reader, you'll probably like it. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Samrat Man Singh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 18:15:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>tag:samrat.me,2011-08-07:blog/2011/08/newsblur-an-awesome-alternative-to-google-reader</guid><category>webapps</category><category>reviews</category></item></channel></rss>